<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-09-19T12:28:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">PITT Initiative on the Computational Social Science</title><subtitle>Website for the PITT Initiative on the Computational Social Science</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Kristina Lerman’s Talk: Why Social Media is So Uniquely Toxic to Our Mental Health</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/09/19/Kristina-Lerman's-Talk-Why-Social-Media-is-So-Uniquely-Toxic-to-Our-Mental-Health.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kristina Lerman’s Talk: Why Social Media is So Uniquely Toxic to Our Mental Health" /><published>2023-09-19T12:00:01-04:00</published><updated>2023-09-19T12:00:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/19/Kristina-Lerman&apos;s-Talk:-Why-Social-Media-is-So-Uniquely-Toxic-to-Our-Mental-Health</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/09/19/Kristina-Lerman&apos;s-Talk-Why-Social-Media-is-So-Uniquely-Toxic-to-Our-Mental-Health.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Speaker:&lt;/b&gt; Kristina Lerman, Principal Scientist, University of Southern California Information Sciences Institute&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Date:&lt;/b&gt; Thursday, September 21, 2023&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Time:&lt;/b&gt; 11:00 am to 12 noon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Location:&lt;/b&gt; 130 N. Bellefield Conference Room, 5th Floor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
There is growing consensus that social media has created a mental health crisis among youth, with severe consequences to their emotional well-being, social functioning, and physical health. This crisis disproportionately affects girls and young women, widening gender gaps and hindering progress towards gender equality. However, the pathways of social media harm are not well understood. In this talk I present evidence for a potential mechanism, exploring it in the context of eating disorders, an often-fatal mental health condition that
includes anorexia, bulimia and binge eating disorder. The rise in eating disorders has been linked to the proliferation of idealized body images on social media; however, the link between social media and eating disorders is more complex. I show how technological affordances of social media can create a “harm spiral” that traps people in toxic echo chambers that promote eating disorders. Specifically, social media makes harmful content easy to discover and its group dynamics encourage people to stay engaged, which exposes them to more harmful content that is deleterious to mental health. To address the youth mental health crisis, we urgently
need to understand how social media harms mental health, and who is vulnerable to its detrimental effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lerman.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kristina Lerman&apos;s presentation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Speaker: Kristina Lerman, Principal Scientist, University of Southern California Information Sciences Institute</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Special Thank You to PittCSS Seminar External Speakers (Spring 2023)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/11/A-Special-Thank-You-to-PittCSS-Seminar-External-Speakers-Spring-2023.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Special Thank You to PittCSS Seminar External Speakers (Spring 2023)" /><published>2023-06-11T11:45:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-11T11:45:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/11/A-Special-Thank-You-to-PittCSS-Seminar-External-Speakers-Spring-2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/11/A-Special-Thank-You-to-PittCSS-Seminar-External-Speakers-Spring-2023.html">&lt;p&gt;Spring 2023 has been an exhilarating season for the PittCSS community! We’ve had the incredible opportunity to learn from a remarkable lineup of external speakers who graced our PittCSS seminars with their expertise and shared their research:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scott Renshaw
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bio: Scott Leo Renshaw is a computational sociologist specializing in social network analysis with research interests in communication dynamics, belief formation, and hazards and disasters. He is a current Post-Doctoral Research Associate at the Center for Informed Democracy &amp;amp; Social-Cybersecurity (IDeas) under Dr. Kathleen Carley.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Talk Title: Communication Across the Spectrum of Hazards and Disasters&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Abstract: This talk presents the micro-communication landscape across the spectrum of hazards and disasters, from the quotidian to the exotic, in the contexts of retransmission and communication dynamics. The first study focuses on hazard communication during quotidian and atypical hazards in the context of the National Weather Service’s use of twitter from 2009 to 2021, where several micro-structural, content, and style related message features are analyzed to understand the properties that make a message more likely to be retransmitted. Our second study looks into the communication occurring in the range of the exotic and atypical end of the spectrum by analyzing public-health communicators on Twitter during the first eight months of the unfolding COVID-19 pandemic, with special emphasis on the use of images and infographics. The final study presented focuses solely on the exotic kind of hazards and disasters through an investigation of 17 radio communication networks during the unfolding events of the 2001 World Trade Center Disaster. In this paper we model these 17 dynamic radio networks through a Relational Event Model approach to understand the role that the social mechanisms of preferential attachment, Institutionalized Coordination Roles (ICR), and conversational inertia play in the communication process of a disrupted environment.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Matt Groh
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bio: Matt Groh is a PhD candidate in the Affective Computing group at the MIT Media Lab and incoming assistant professor of Management and Organizations at Northwestern University’s Kellogg School of Management. His research examines human-AI collaboration with a focus on misinformation, medical diagnosis, and empathy. Before MIT, Matt cofounded a startup and worked as a data scientist at multiple startups, a non-profit, the World Bank, and DARPA. Matt has a bachelor’s degree from Middlebury College where he majored in economics and minored in Arabic and mathematics and a master’s degree from MIT in Media Arts and Sciences. He likes to ride his bicycle.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Talk Title: Diagnostic Accuracy across Light and Dark Skin by Specialists, Generalists, and Physician-Machine Partnerships&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Abstract: Recent advances in deep learning systems (DLS) for image-based medical diagnosis demonstrate the potential to augment clinical decision-making, but the effectiveness of physician-machine partnerships remains an open question because physicians and algorithms are prone to systematic errors on underrepresented populations. We present results from a large-scale digital experiment (N=390 board-certified dermatologists and N=460 primary care physicians from 39 countries) to evaluate the accuracy of physicians submitting up to 4 differential diagnoses on 364 images of 46 skin conditions in a store-and-forward teledermatology simulation. We find specialists achieve 38% accuracy, specialists and generalists alike are 4 percentage points less accurate on images of dark skin than light skin, and fair DLS decision support reduces accuracy disparities and improves specialists’ leading diagnosis accuracy by 33%. These results reveal image-based diagnosis is challenging especially for underrepresented populations but well-designed physician-machine partnerships can enhance physician performance and reduce disparities across skin color.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Max Goplerud
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bio: Max Goplerud is an Assistant Professor of Political Science. His primary research creates new methods to facilitate political science research by leveraging the intersection of Bayesian methods and machine learning. These methods are focused on topics such as heterogeneous effects, hierarchical models, and ideal point estimation. He also is interested in understanding legislative behavior using text-as-data in a comparative context including studies on Europe, the United States, and Japan. He received his PhD from the Department of Government at Harvard University in 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Talk Title: Visualizing Democracy Using Covariate-Adjusted Principal Curves&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Abstract: A common task in data analysis in social science is to quantify and visually present the potentially non-linear relationship between a set of variables that lack a clear causal or temporal ordering. Principal curves provide one solution by drawing a single smooth curve that runs through the middle of the entire distribution of the data. However, it is often the case that the relationship between the variables differs based on known moderators. Therefore, allowing the curve to vary based on those covariates is crucial to accurately representing the underlying relationship. We propose “covariate-adjusted principal curves” to allow for an arbitrary number of moderators to affect the shape of the curve. Our method extends classic methods for fitting principal curves (e.g. splines) to their covariate-adjusted analogues (e.g. varying-coefficient models). Our motivating application is the empirical study of democracy. Using an influential existing study, we demonstrate that the relationship between two major dimensions of democracy (contestation and participation) has changed dramatically over the past two centuries—even when adjusting for other moderators such as colonial history and national income. Existing techniques for quantifying the changing relationship, e.g. correlations based on splitting the data into discrete time periods, falls short at illustrating this shift.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mike Colaresi
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bio: Michael Colaresi is the Associate Vice Provost for Data Science, Director of the Pitt Disinformation Lab, and Research and Academic Director of the Institute for Cyber Law, Policy, and Security. He also co-directs the Computational Social Science BS degree and is the William S. Dietrich II Professor of Political Science at the University of Pittsburgh. His research is focused at the intersection of international relations and computational social science where he studies the application of Bayesian computation and machine learning to topics including how human rights are changing over time, where and when to predict political violence at high spatial and temporal resolution, and why disinformation poses both international and local challenges to democratic communities. At Pitt, he teaches Scientific Computation for Social Scientists, Text as Data, Bayesian Computation, The Domestic Politics of International Conflict in the Digital Age, and Introduction to Computational Social Science.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Talk Title: Move It or Lose It: Introducing pseudo-Earth Mover Divergence as a Context-sensitive Metric for Evaluating and Improving Forecasting and Prediction Systems&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Abstract: Prediction systems necessarily utilize a suite of metrics to evaluate and compare models and ultimately guide inferences about the world. However, conventional measures of model performance, such as accuracy, Brier scores, F1 (and its components), AUROC, and AUPR solely utilize observation-by-observation, also known as bin-by-bin, comparisons between the distribution of predictions and the actual values. Any meaningful connections, be they social or physical, between observations, what we can think of as the data settings where predictions will be used, are ignored in these calculations. Thus, a system that consistently produced very close misses, for example in time and/or space, would not be preferred to a system that consistently emitted more distant but otherwise identical mistaken predictions. This bin-by-bin default approach is not assumption-free regarding the settings in which predictions are utilized: they explicitly encode the judgment that a prediction system’s output is being used within a completely disconnected network structure across observations. This assumption might be reasonable in some cases, but it is particularly problematic in computational social science where there are both enduring (eg. time serial and panel) as well as emerging (eg. high resolution spatial-temporal, and network) data settings where the connections between observations have enormous implications for the overall costs and benefits of incorporating model-based predictions into decisions. Forecasting political violence, famines, extreme weather events, and cybersecurity exploits and intrusions, are all examples where the distribution of predictions versus the actual values can be the difference between life and death or security and insecurity. Herein, we propose a new network-based context-sensitive performance metric, pseudo-Earth Mover Divergence (pEMDiv) to accelerate progress and discoveries in these, and related, areas. We explain how pEMDiv expands on Earth Mover Distance (EMD), how it can be used for binary prediction problems with hard or soft predictions, point predictions on a continuous scale, as well as probabilistic predictions over a discrete ordered state space.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we bid adieu to Spring 2023, we express our deepest gratitude to these speakers for sharing their knowledge and unique perspectives with the PittCSS community.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spring 2023 has been an exhilarating season for the PittCSS community! We’ve had the incredible opportunity to learn from a remarkable lineup of external speakers who graced our PittCSS seminars with their expertise and shared their research:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nefriana and Alireza Presented at DINS PhD Student Speaker Series</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/23/nefriana-and-alireza-in-dins-seminar.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nefriana and Alireza Presented at DINS PhD Student Speaker Series" /><published>2023-03-23T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-23T12:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/23/nefriana-and-alireza-in-dins-seminar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/23/nefriana-and-alireza-in-dins-seminar.html">&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to share with you an exciting event that took place on March 23, 2023. Our members, Nefriana and Alireza, had the incredible opportunity to present their research at the University of Pittsburgh DINS Seminar Series. The seminar was attended not only by current SCI students but also by incoming PhD students who were eager to gain insights into the life of a PhD student in SCI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nefriana and Alireza had the opportunity to share their research findings in this seminar series after their successful defense of their preliminary examination a week before, along with Yiling, who had also previously shared her research at the DINS PhD Student Speaker Series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/alireza_dins_seminar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alireza presentation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/nefriana_alireza_dins_poster.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alireza presentation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We are thrilled to share with you an exciting event that took place on March 23, 2023. Our members, Nefriana and Alireza, had the incredible opportunity to present their research at the University of Pittsburgh DINS Seminar Series. The seminar was attended not only by current SCI students but also by incoming PhD students who were eager to gain insights into the life of a PhD student in SCI.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Yiling’s article is accepted by Journal of Informetrics</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/11/30/Yiling's-article-is-accepted-by-journal-of-informetrics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yiling’s article is accepted by Journal of Informetrics" /><published>2021-11-30T11:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-11-30T11:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/11/30/Yiling&apos;s-article-is-accepted-by-journal-of%20informetrics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/11/30/Yiling&apos;s-article-is-accepted-by-journal-of-informetrics.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lyl010.github.io/yilinglin/&quot;&gt;Yiling’s&lt;/a&gt; recent work analyzed millions of research articles published over four decades to understand how yesterday’s novelty forms today’s scientific conventions, which condition the novelty-and surprise-of tomorrow’s breakthroughs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper, titled “New Directions in Science Emerge from Disconnection and Discord,” is accepted to be published by &lt;em&gt;Journal of Informetrics (JOI)&lt;/em&gt;, a peer-reviewed journal which publishes high-quality research on quantitative aspects of information science. JOI’s impact factor is 5.1 and ranks Q1 in Computer Science Applications, Library and Information Sciences, Management Science and Operations Research, and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the final acceptance of this paper, Yiling had presented it across research groups and communities and triggered warmly discussions in &lt;a href=&quot;https://scinlp.org/&quot;&gt;SciNLP 2021&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ic2s2-2021.ethz.ch/&quot;&gt;IC2S2 2021&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://buyi08.wixsite.com/yi-bu&quot;&gt;Yi Bu’s &lt;/a&gt; group at Peking University, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bvasiles.github.io/&quot;&gt;Bogdan Vasilescu’s&lt;/a&gt; group at Carnegie Mellon University, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://yingding.ischool.utexas.edu/&quot;&gt;Ying Ding’s&lt;/a&gt; group at the University of Texas at Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2103.03398&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Yiling’s recent work analyzed millions of research articles published over four decades to understand how yesterday’s novelty forms today’s scientific conventions, which condition the novelty-and surprise-of tomorrow’s breakthroughs.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Guest Speaker Yong-Yeol ‘YY’ Ahn on Representation learning for computational imagination</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/10/22/yy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guest Speaker Yong-Yeol ‘YY’ Ahn on Representation learning for computational imagination" /><published>2021-10-22T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-10-22T12:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/10/22/yy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/10/22/yy.html">&lt;p&gt;Abstract:
Computational social science leverages new data sources and computational methods to expand the “sociological imagination”, connecting individual milieus to the wider sociological conditions. Beyond extending the existing approaches, can new computational tools also help expanding the scope of our imagination? In this talk, I will talk about how simple representation learning techniques   (esp. “word2vec”) can allow us to think about the text and network data in new ways. In particular, I will discuss how a subtle, less known bias in the word2vec model lets us do better ground the model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker Bio: 
Yong-Yeol (YY) Ahn is an Associate Professor at Indiana University School of Informatics, Computing, and Engineering. He was a Visiting Professor at MIT during 2020-2021. Before joining Indiana University, he worked as a postdoctoral research associate at the Center for Complex Network Research at Northeastern University and as a visiting researcher at the Center for Cancer Systems Biology at Dana-Farber Cancer Institute after earning his PhD in Statistical Physics from KAIST in 2008. His research focuses on developing network science and machine learning methods, and applying them to complex social and biological systems. He is a recipient of several awards including Microsoft Research Faculty Fellowship and LinkedIn Economic Graph Challenge.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Abstract: Computational social science leverages new data sources and computational methods to expand the “sociological imagination”, connecting individual milieus to the wider sociological conditions. Beyond extending the existing approaches, can new computational tools also help expanding the scope of our imagination? In this talk, I will talk about how simple representation learning techniques (esp. “word2vec”) can allow us to think about the text and network data in new ways. In particular, I will discuss how a subtle, less known bias in the word2vec model lets us do better ground the model.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Guest Speaker Peter Dodds on Ousiometrics and Telegnomics: Distant measurement of historical timelines, story turbulence, and essential meaning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/10/06/dodds.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guest Speaker Peter Dodds on Ousiometrics and Telegnomics: Distant measurement of historical timelines, story turbulence, and essential meaning" /><published>2021-10-06T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-10-06T12:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/10/06/dodds</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/10/06/dodds.html">&lt;p&gt;First, this Friday’s seminar will occur at a slightly earlier time than normal: 11:45am-12:45pm. Please use the usual Zoom link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Friday’s seminar presentation will be our first external talk given by Prof. &lt;a href=&quot;https://pdodds.w3.uvm.edu/&quot;&gt;Peter Sheridan Dodds&lt;/a&gt; (UVM). Peter will be presenting on “Ousiometrics and Telegnomics: Distant measurement of historical timelines, story turbulence, and essential meaning.” The talk will cover how to leverage collective utterances (e.g., tweets) to quantify societal well-being, cultural trends, and the emergence/spread of stories. 
Peter’s research focuses on system-level, big data problems in many areas including language and stories, sociotechnical systems, Earth sciences, biology, and ecology. Peter has created (and constantly evolves) a series of complex systems courses starting with Principles of Complex Systems. He co-runs the Computational Story Lab with Chris Danforth which is known for “blatantly fun research.”
For those interested, (completely optional) related background reading includes: Experimental study of inequality and unpredictability in an artificial cultural market (Science. aka the Music Lab study), The geography of happiness: Connecting Twitter sentiment and expression, demographics, and objective characteristics of place  (Plos ONE), and Human language reveals a universal positivity bias (PNAS)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">First, this Friday’s seminar will occur at a slightly earlier time than normal: 11:45am-12:45pm. Please use the usual Zoom link.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Yiling’s article is accepted to present at SciNLP</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/19/Yiling's-article-is-accepted-to-present-at-SciNLP.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yiling’s article is accepted to present at SciNLP" /><published>2021-09-19T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-09-19T12:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/09/19/Yiling&apos;s-article-is-accepted-to-present-at-SciNLP</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/19/Yiling&apos;s-article-is-accepted-to-present-at-SciNLP.html">&lt;p&gt;Science is built upon scholarship consensus that changes over time. This raises the question of how revolutionary theories and assumptions are evaluated and accepted into the norm of science as the setting for the next scientific revolution. Yiling’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://lyl010.github.io/yilinglin/&quot;&gt;recent work&lt;/a&gt; analyzed millions of research articles published over four decades and revealed the scarcity (~2%) of highly novel work, the higher chance (25%) they disrupt existing research rather than developing it, and its long-shot nature (it takes ten years or longer to recognize a novel work, over which period only 20% scholars survived). Yiling’s work also provides one of the first computational models reformulating Uzzi Atypicality, a prominent novelty measure in the Science of Science, as the distance across the latent knowledge spaces learned by neural networks. The evolution of this knowledge space characterizes how yesterday’s novelty forms today’s scientific conventions, which condition the novelty–and surprise–of tomorrow’s breakthroughs. This paper is accepted to present at &lt;a href=&quot;https://scinlp.org/&quot;&gt;SciNLP&lt;/a&gt;, a community aiming to bring together researchers from diverse fields who are interested in building computational systems that extract, represent the knowledge in scientific texts, and/or provide humans better access to such knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2103.03398&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Science is built upon scholarship consensus that changes over time. This raises the question of how revolutionary theories and assumptions are evaluated and accepted into the norm of science as the setting for the next scientific revolution. Yiling’s recent work analyzed millions of research articles published over four decades and revealed the scarcity (~2%) of highly novel work, the higher chance (25%) they disrupt existing research rather than developing it, and its long-shot nature (it takes ten years or longer to recognize a novel work, over which period only 20% scholars survived). Yiling’s work also provides one of the first computational models reformulating Uzzi Atypicality, a prominent novelty measure in the Science of Science, as the distance across the latent knowledge spaces learned by neural networks. The evolution of this knowledge space characterizes how yesterday’s novelty forms today’s scientific conventions, which condition the novelty–and surprise–of tomorrow’s breakthroughs. This paper is accepted to present at SciNLP, a community aiming to bring together researchers from diverse fields who are interested in building computational systems that extract, represent the knowledge in scientific texts, and/or provide humans better access to such knowledge.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Detecting Workplace Skills from University Syllabi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/03/detecting-workplace-skills-in-university-syllabi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Detecting Workplace Skills from University Syllabi" /><published>2021-09-03T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-09-03T12:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/09/03/detecting-workplace-skills-in-university-syllabi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/03/detecting-workplace-skills-in-university-syllabi.html">&lt;p&gt;Which colleges give their students relevant skills for the future of work? Which majors or fields of study have limited effectiveness as workforce development? Data on skills and workplace activities are essential for describing labor trends in the workforce, but data on the skills taught during workforce development—in higher education in particular—remain absent. Although studies of job postings and US Department of Labor ONET data describe both the supply and demand side of a polarized job market, few studies describe the specific skills taught to college students, who then enter the workforce as “high-skill” workers. This project will fill this gap using a novel data set of 10 million university course syllabi to empirically study the skills (e.g., ONET workplace activities) taught in courses over the last decade according to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensyllabus.org/&quot;&gt;Open Syllabus Project&lt;/a&gt;. This project will compare the empirical skills taught in university/college classrooms with labor data from the US Department of Labor and a data set of millions of worker resumes to assess the role of higher education in job polarization, wealth inequality, and to identify the educational foundations for adaptable workers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Which colleges give their students relevant skills for the future of work? Which majors or fields of study have limited effectiveness as workforce development? Data on skills and workplace activities are essential for describing labor trends in the workforce, but data on the skills taught during workforce development—in higher education in particular—remain absent. Although studies of job postings and US Department of Labor ONET data describe both the supply and demand side of a polarized job market, few studies describe the specific skills taught to college students, who then enter the workforce as “high-skill” workers. This project will fill this gap using a novel data set of 10 million university course syllabi to empirically study the skills (e.g., ONET workplace activities) taught in courses over the last decade according to the Open Syllabus Project. This project will compare the empirical skills taught in university/college classrooms with labor data from the US Department of Labor and a data set of millions of worker resumes to assess the role of higher education in job polarization, wealth inequality, and to identify the educational foundations for adaptable workers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fall 2021 Student Welcome Picnic</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/20/fall-picnic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fall 2021 Student Welcome Picnic" /><published>2021-08-20T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-20T12:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/20/fall-picnic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/20/fall-picnic.html">&lt;p&gt;We are hosting a cross-group student welcome picnic at xx Park. Some description here…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;schedule&quot;&gt;Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Staturday, September 18, 10:00am-2pm, we will …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attending&quot;&gt;Attending&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to attend or help prepare ….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;details&quot;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organizers of the event are Peter, Rosta, Morgan, Lingfei, and Yu-Ru.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We are hosting a cross-group student welcome picnic at xx Park. Some description here…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello PittCSS!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/20/hello-pittcss.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello PittCSS!" /><published>2021-08-20T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-20T12:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/20/hello-pittcss</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/20/hello-pittcss.html">&lt;p&gt;We launch the PITT Initiative on the Computational Social Science to connect to everyone who are interested in doing CSS research.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We launch the PITT Initiative on the Computational Social Science to connect to everyone who are interested in doing CSS research.</summary></entry></feed>